Finding Aid for the Extremist Book Collection,
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Extremist Book Collection,
552
4 boxes (2.0 linear ft.)
University of California, Los Angeles. Library. Department of Special Collections. Los Angeles, California 90095-1575
This collection contains a variety of extremist literature predominantly from the 1930s to the 1960s. The collection consists of books espousing political viewpoints of the extreme left and right, extremist periodicals, and bookdealer catalogs.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Advance notice required for access.
Additional Physical Form Available
A copy of the original version of this online finding aid is available at the UCLA Department of Special Collections for in-house consultation and may be obtained for a fee. Please contact:
Public Services Division
UCLA Library, Department of Special Collections
Room A1713, Charles E. Young Research Library
Box 951575
Los Angeles, CA 90095-1575
Telephone: 310/825-4988 (10:00 a.m. - 4:45 p.m., Pacific Time)
Email: spec-coll@library.ucla.edu
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 4232998
Biography
This collection contains a variety of extremist literature predominantly from the 1930s to the 1960s including writings by Che Guevara, Karl Marx, V.M. Molotov, and Joseph Stalin.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of books espousing political viewpoints of the extreme left and right, extremist periodicals, and bookdealer catalogs. Includes the periodicals The communist, Dialectics, and Political affairs. Left wing books include writings by Che Guevara, Karl Marx, V.M. Molotov, and Joseph Stalin. Right wing books include Marilyn R. Allen's Alien Minorities and Mongrelization, Elizabeth Dilling's The Roosevelt Red Record and its Background, and Phyllis Schlafly's The Gravediggers.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Alternative publications.; Literature of prejudice.; Propaganda.
Container List
- Books
  - Capell, Frank A. The Threat From Within. New Port Beach (California): Herald of Freedom 1963. (Box 1)
  - Carpenter, John. Extremism U.S.A.Phoenix: Associated Professional Services 1964. (Box 1)
  - Cincinnatus. Veritas Vincit. War! War! War!n.p. 1940. (Box 1)
  - Crane, Philip. The Democrats Dilemma. Chicago: Henry Regnery 1964. (Box 1)
  - Fortas, Abe. Concerning Dissent and Civil Disobedience. New York: New American Library. Another copy, varient. 1968. (Box 1)
  - Frommer, Arthur. Goldwater From A to Z. A Critical Handbook. New York: Pocket Books 1964. (Box 1)
  - Green, G.F. The International Jew The World's Foremost Problem.Herts (England): Green 1949. (Box 1)
  - Guevara, Che. Che Guevara on Vietnam and World Revolution. New York: Merit 1967. (Box 1)
  - Haley, J. Evetts. A Texan Looks at Lyndon. A Study in Illegimate Power. Canyon (Texas): Palo Duro Press 1964. (Box 1)
  - Huberman, Leo. The Labor Spy Racket. New York: Modern Age Books 1937. (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Frank Woodruff. The Octopus. Omaha: Author 1940. (Box 1)
  - Johnson, John J. The United States and the Latin American Left Wings. Stanford (California): Center for Research in International Studies 1967. (Box 1)
  - Lasell, Helen P. Power Behind Government Today. New York: Liberty Publications 1963. (Box 1)
  - Lippman, Walter. The Stakes of Diplomacy. New York: Henry Holt & Company 1915. (Box 1)
  - Luce, Phillip Abbott. Road to Revolution: Communist Guerilla Warfare in the U.S.A.San Diego: Viewpoint Books 1967. (Box 1)
  - Manking United. A Challenge to Mad Ambition and The Money Changers.n.p.: The International Registration Bureau 1938. (Box 1)
  - Moravec, Charles. Logos. Arlington (Texas): Moasic Press, (vol.1: But Man Proud Man) 1965. (Box 1)
  - Morris, Robert. No Wonder We Are Losing. New York: The Bookmailer 1958. (Box 1)
  - Nock, Albert Jay. The Myth of a Guilty Nation. New York: Huebsch Incorporated 1922. (Box 1)
  - Peck, James. Underdogs vs Upperdogs. Canterbury (New Hampshire): Greenleaf 1969. (Box 1)
  - Pritt, D.N. Star Spangled Shadow. London (England): Frederick Muller 1947. (Box 1)
  - Storm, Wayne. International Money Power Behind World Revolution. Shreveport (Louisiana): Storm Publishing 1966. (Box 1)
  - Stormer, John A. None Dare Call It Treason. Florissant (Missouri): Liberty Bell Press 1964. (Box 1)
  - Thompson, Dorothy. The Truth About Communism. Washington, D.C.: Public Affairs Press 1948. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Charles R., Jr. Concentration Camps U.S.A.New York: Marzani & Munsell 1966. (Box 2)
  - Allen, Marilyn R. Alien Minorities and Mongrelization. Boston: Meador 1949. (Box 2)
  - Artune, Frederick. The Grapes of Madness. The Racial Crisis in Perspective. n.p. 1969. (Box 2)
  - Byfield, Robert S. The Fifth Weapon. New York: The Bookmailer 1954. (Box 2)
  - Beaty, John. The Iron Curtain Over America. Dallas: Wildenson, 1952. Another copy, Varient. 1962. (Box 2)
  - Chodorov, Frank. The Income Tax: Root of all Evil. Portland (Indiana): Independence Foundation 1957. (Box 2)
  - Macdonald, Andrew. The Turner Diaries. Arlington (Virginia): National Vanguard Books 1980. (Box 2)
    Removed for cataloging, 1996.
  - Dilling, Elizabeth. The Red Network; A Who's Who and Handbook of Rdaicalism for Patriots. Chicago: Author 1934. (Box 2)
  - Dilling, Elizabeth. The Roosevelt Red Record and Its Background. Chicago: Author 1936. (Box 2)
  - McBirnie, W.S. How to Predict What Our Enemies Will Do. Glendale (California): Author n.d. (Box 2)
  - Meeker, C.A. Shysterism U.S.A. Albuquerque, Fox 1967. (Box 2)
  - Schlafly, Phyllis. The Gravediggers. Alton (Illinois): Pere Marquette Press 1964. (Box 2)
  - Shafer, Paul W. The Turning of the Tides. New Canaan (Connecticut): The Long House 1965. (Box 2)
  - U.S. Government House of Representitives. Committee on Un-American Activities. Guide to Subversive Organizations and Publications. 1961 (Box 2)
  - U.S. Government House of Representitives. Committee on Un-American Activities. Supplement to Cumulative Index to Publications of The Committee on Un-American Activities 1955 through 1960. 1961. (Box 2)
  - We Accuse. A Powerful Statement of the New Political Anger in America. Berkeley (California): Diablo Press 1965. (Box 2)
  - Wynn, Milton J. Why I Hate the Nazis. New York: ACA Gallery 1945. (Box 2)
  - Considine, Bob. How Russia Stole America's Atomic Secrets. n.p.: International News Services 1951. (Box 3)
  - Dewey, John. Impressions of Soviet Russia and the Revolutionary World. New York: New Republic 1929. (Box 3)
  - Hamilton, Mary. Freedom Riders Speak For Themselves. Detroit: News & Letters 1961. (Box 3)
  - Lowry, Edith. Migrants of the Crops: They Starve That We May Eat. New York: Council of Women For Home Missions and Missionary Education Movement 1938. (Box 3)
  - Marx, Karl. Wage-Labor and Capital. New York: International Publishers 1932. (Box 3)
  - Molotov, V. The Soviet Union in 1942. The Third Five-Year Plan. New York: Workers Library Publishers 1939. (Box 3)
  - Program of the Communist International Together With Its Constitution. New York: Workers Library Publishers 1936. (Box 3)
  - Stalin, Joseph. Foundations of Leninism. New York: International Publishers 1934. (Box 3)
  - Stalin, Joseph. Mastering Bolshevism. New York: Workers Library Publishers 1938. (Box 3)
  - Voices From Russia. St. Louis: The Melting Pot ca.1918. (Box 3)
- Periodicals
  - The Communist. New York: Workers Library Publishers. (Box 3)
    - September 1938.
    - November 1938.
    - March 1939.
    - April 1940.
    - June 1940.
    - May 1942.
    - March 1943.
    - June 1943.
    - November 1943.
    - February 1944.
    - April 1944.
    - October 1944.
  - Dialectics. New York: Critics Group. (Box 3)
    - no.1-8
  - Political Affairs. New York: New Century Publishers. (Box 3)
    - July 1945
    - October 1945.
    - September 1946.
    - October 1946.
    - January 1947.
    - February 1947.
    - September 1947.
    - June 1948
    - November 1948.
    - December 1948.
  - The New Mythology of Racial Equality. New York: The Truth Seeker Company, Incorporated 1963. (Box 4)
  - Howard, Peter. Design for Dedication. Chicago: Henry Regnery Company 1964. (Box 4)
  - Kluckhohn, Frank L. America: Listen!Derby (Connecticut): Monarch Books, Incorporated 1961. (Box 4)
  - Lane, Lieutenant-Colonel A.H. The Alien Menace. London: H.A. Kings and Sons, Limited 1928. (Box 4)
  - Schafly, Phyllis. A Choice not an Echo. Alton(Illinois): Pere Marquette Press 1964. (Box 4)
  - Schafly, Phyllis and Chester Ward. Strike from Space. Alton (Illinois): Pere Marquette Press 1965. (Box 4)
  - Stormer, John A. None Dare Call It Treason. Florissant (Missouri): Liberty Bell Press 1964. (Copy 2). (Box 4)
- Bibliographies
  - The Radical Right, Catalog #15. Burbank: Book Castle Incorporated. (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous ephemera: includes bookdealer catalogs. (Box 4, Folder 1)